



hello@kevinchoy.ca

in /kgchoy

778.829.9356

PROFILE

I specialize in user experience research and design, with a desire to get to know how current and potential users might use an interactive product throughout every step of the development process, from conceptualization to product evaluation. My overall passion for design compliments my expertise in web coding and programming, allowing me to translate my design ideas into reality. Finally, I have professional experience in marketing and communications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Design	Languages	Other Software & Platforms
Axure	HTML5 / CSS3	Bootstrap
Balsamiq	JavaScript (+jQuery, D3.js, three.js)	Git
Illustrator	Java (+ Android APIs)	Eloqua
Photoshop	Python	Google Analytics
InDesign	C++	Amazon Web Services

CONCEPTS & KNOWLEDGE

A/B testing Personas Usability testing
Heuristic evaluation Rapid prototyping User scenarios
Interaction design Storyboarding Visual design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Email & Website Developer/Designer (Co-op)

ACTIVE Network

January 2014 – August 2014

Roles

- Designed and coded emails, forms, and landing pages in HTML/CSS, additionally using JavaScript and the Bootstrap framework when appropriate
- · Set them up for distribution and viewing using the Eloqua marketing automation software
- Created graphic assets for digital marketing materials
- Ensured all designs followed corporate branding standards

Outcomes

Created high-quality emails and landing pages while frequently working within tight deadlines. Greatly contributed to marketing and communications objectives, and drove leads and conversions.

Communications Research Assistant (Co-op)

BCcampus

January 2013 – August 2013

Roles

- Coordinated a usability test of their corporate website; researched use cases, designed the test, recruited participants, and facilitated tests at their workplaces
- Facilitated a major reorganization of their Confluence corporate wiki after consulting with their staff, coordinated software tutorial sessions, and provided technical support
- · Created a biweekly marketing newsletter using Campaign Monitor

Outcomes

Strengthened communication and collaboration between BCcampus and their users and stakeholders (academic faculty, administrators, and staff), plus internally between their teams of employees. My report of findings and recommendations after the usability test guided the design of their new responsive website.

Kevin Choy kevinchoy.ca

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer and Web Designer

New Dawn Immigration Canada

May 2016 - Present

Ongoing freelance project to do a visual brand identity redesign for my client, an immigration consulting firm. I have finished conceptualizing and designing their new logo and stationery, while also ensuring I matched my client's requests and preferences. I am currently designing a new website using WordPress.

DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT COURSE PROJECTS

UX, UI, and Interaction Designer & Researcher

Community Builder

October 2015 - December 2015

Our team of four developed the interface and interactions for an Android app that allowed people to organize, search, and volunteer for community events within their neighbourhoods, promoting physical community engagement.

Roles

- Created scenarios, personas, and a journey map to explore user goals and task flows
- Rapidly developed and refined interface designs, ranging from low-fidelity paper wireframes to
 high-fidelity Axure prototypes, on a weekly cycle using the agile methodology, taking into account
 design critiques and usability test results
- Created a usability test plan and its tasks, and facilitated the majority of the tests

Visual Analyst and Programmer

Urban Sprawl Visualizer

July 2014 – August 2014

Our two-person group created a web-based visualization to help users understand the factors that influence urban sprawl in the United States, and what factors are common amongst cities with similar sprawl statistics.

Roles

- Researched and proposed different visualization methods to display information from a large data set
- Built the final visualization, which implemented a hybrid between a scatterplot and star plot, using JavaScript and the D3.js data visualization library

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Vice President of Education

Burnaby Mountain Toastmasters

October 2014 - Present

The goal of our Toastmasters club at SFU is to help members improve their public speaking skills in a fun, friendly, and supportive environment. I monitor each member's educational goals, coordinate the weekly club meetings and member roles, and ensure that new members receive an orientation to the club and are assigned a mentor.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Interactive Arts & Technology (Concentration in Interactive Systems), Minor in Computing Science

Simon Fraser University

2009 - 2015

As a graduate from the School of Interactive Arts & Technology at SFU, I learned the skills and tools to not only create both elegant and functional designs, but to also build the technologies and experiences that increasingly shape our lives. My concentration, Interactive Systems, focuses on the interaction between computer systems and users.